

Jurgen Stevens

Full Stack Software Engineer

CONTACT

Phone: (847) 802-2801

Email: jurgen.stevens@yahoo.com Location: Chicago, IL 60608

LinkedIn:

linkedin.com/in/jurgenstevens/
Portfolio: jurgenstevens.dev/
Github: github.com/jurgenstevens

EDUCATION

General Assembly

Software Engineering Immersive Sept 2019 - Dec 2019 Chicago, IL

Illinois Media School

Media and Broadcasting Jan 2012 - Jan 2013 Chicago, IL

SKILLS

HARD SKILLS:

Git | HTML | CSS | SASS | JavaScript |
Python | MongoDB | Express.js |
Node.js | React.js | React Hooks |
React Router DOM | Flask | Django |
PostgreSQL | Heroku | Github |
Notion | Slack | Trello | Spanish
(Fluent) | Italian (Converstational) |
Bosnian (Beginner)

SOFT SKILLS:

Empathetic | Moral Booster | Understanding | Strong Support | Take Pride In Work | Team Player | Open Minded | Enthusiastic | Optimistic | Determined | Ambitious

CERTIFICATIONS

Illinois Media School:

Certification in Media and Broadcasting attained in 2013

General Assembly:

Software Engineering Immersive Certificate attained in 2019

SUMMARY

Chicago-based Full Stack Software Developer with 3+ years of self taught, immersive bootcamp, and instructional experience. I want to put my programming skills to good use and be a part of something that has a beneficial impact on peoples' lives.

WORK EXPERIENCE

General Assembly

Instructional Associate, Chicago, IL Remote, *Mar 2021 - Present*

- Made sure students understood concepts such as OOP, Functional Programming, MVC design and RESTful architecture.
- Created a welcoming and comfortable environment for students to come to us, the instructional team, with any challenges instead of suffering in silence.
- Successfully guided students trying to reach MVP on their MEN and MERN Stack projects through each stage of the process to achieve CRUDability on the models they needed for their projects.
- Provided input on students' code reviews for four unit projects for each of the previous three cohorts.
- Lectured for numerous cohorts of 20+ students on HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and creating an API using Express.js, Node.js, and MongoDB.

Palmolive Condominium

Doorman, Chicago, IL, Oct 2020 - Jun 2021

- Provided a warm, courteous, and professional welcome, greeting, and farewell to all residents and guests.
- Answered the lobby phone and returned calls in a timely manner.
- Ensured there was no suspicious activity in or near the premises.
- Assisted with mail, parcels, phone calls, car requests, grocery and luggage management.

Second Life Mac

Audit Department Trainer, Skokie, IL, Sept 2018 - Jun 2020

- Trained new staff and double-checked that they were grading used Apple items accurately.
- Ensured that every batch of Apple goods received had their memory deleted and settings restored to factory defaults.
- Reported to the warehouse manager on the progress of Apple product batches on a regular basis.